Joshua Webb

07496166093 joshuawebb2007@proton.me

Personal profile

Hello there, my name is Joshua David Webb a programmer of 4 years and a general IT and tech enthusiast, I specialize in cryptography, networking and programming. Besides my IT skills I am a generally positive thinking person and I'm never scared to try something new as well as being able to lead a group and follow instructions.

Skills

Digital literacy

I have been programming for over 4 years now I have an intermediate level knowledge of Python as well as knowledge in Rust, web development frameworks such as svelte kit as well as having good computational thinking.

Teamwork

I have been doing a holiday club called Chattabox+ for 3 years now and every year everyone on the camp is put into a group and expected to work together to complete games and to chat together, this experience has made me really good at organizing a team as well as taking feedback from my team to better our skills as a group. An example of how I led our group was during Laser Tag, I have experience with these situations so I was able to organize my team into a strong formation that allowed us to take first place and win that event.

Working under pressure

I have a strong ability to stay focused even in high pressure situations. This allows me to approach any task with a clear and logical mindset.

Problem solving

Thanks to my interest in programming I have gained excellent problem solving skills. I enjoy working through a complex problem and breaking it down into smaller more digestible chunks before putting it back together and finding the solution, I will also almost always come up with more than one way to solve a problem just in case one way turns out not to work.

Work experience

October 2024 - Present

Volunteering - The Air Ambulance charity shop Oundle

I volunteered at the Air Ambulance to get vital till experience and how to handle customers in a professional setting.

July 2024 - Present

Gardening - A parents friends house

As a part time job I was asked to help with a garden restoration project they were completing at the time, as a younger person I was able to get into smaller places where they could not get to. This was also very fun for me since as a programmer I don't get out to much and reconnecting with nature was fun.

August 2024

Young leader - Chattabox+

I have been a young leader at Chattabox for 3 years, this role would be in the morning helping the younger children with the main session encouraging them and being supportive and when Chattabox ended at lunch time, Chattabox+ would continue through the afternoon where all of the young leaders player games building teamwork skills and had a great time bonding together.

June 2024 - August 2024

Cleaning - My home

During study leave for my GCSE exams I was tasked each day I was off with not only completing revision for my upcoming exams but also to do basic cleaning jobs such as sweeping, mopping, wiping down sides and much more,. This continued on through the time I was off till the summer holidays.

June 2024

Cybersecurity Engineer - Forage

AIG Shields Up: Cybersecurity virtual experience program on Forage - June 2024

- * Completed a cybersecurity threat analysis simulation for the Cyber Defense Unit, staying updated on CISA publications.
- * Researched and understood reported vulnerabilities, showcasing analytical skills in cybersecurity.
- * Drafted a clear and concise email to guide teams on vulnerability

remediation.

* Utilized Python skills to write a script for ethical hacking, avoiding ransom payments by bruteforcing decryption keys.

https://forage-uploads-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/completion-certificates/AlG/2ZFnEGEDKTQMtEv9C_AlG_q4qNRnSiANMrJvzgq_1717420676260_completion_certificate.pdf

Education

September 2024 - Present

Digital Skills & IT Intermediate (Level 2) - Corby Tresham College

This is the first college course I will be taking, I will also be attending English lessons to get the grade 4 I require to re enroll next year and complete the T Level I was hoping to do in 2024.

September 2023 - July 2024

Btec DIT - Prince William School

I completed a Btec in Digital Information Technology at Prince William School in 2024 which developed my skills with Excel, planning events and projects with tools such as Gant charts and overall teamwork skills.

September 2023 - July 2024

Religious Education - Prince William School

I completed the Religious Education course at Prince William School which taught me about life and ethics, this course made me more understanding as a person.

September 2023 - July 2024

English - Prince William School

I achieved a 3 in English language and literature however got a Distinction in the speaking assessment. I am resitting the Language aspect at Corby Tresham College alongside my IT course.

September 2023 - July 2024

Maths - Prince William School

I achieved a grade 4 in Mathematics.

Other interests

July 2024 - Present

Climbing

I have taken up climbing as a hobby since I have always found climbing fun, even since a young age I have always found a way to climb something that seemed impossible for me at the time, this has proven to be a great way to get some exercise into my programming filled days whilst still having fun.

September 2020 - Present

Coding

I have been an avid programmer for over 4 years now starting with bat and bash scripts on Linux and Windows and slowly progressing onto Python as my first "proper" language this taught me the fundamentals of programming and helped me with my Problem solving skills, as the years have gone on I have learnt web development languages such as HTML5, CSS3 and JS.

References available on request